Inventory of the Richard M. and Robert B. Sherman papers, 1963-1969
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Richard M. and Robert B. Sherman papers
1963-1969
Sherman, Richard M., 1928-
Sherman, Robert B.
03222
1.64 cubic feet (2 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
This collection contains music scores, notes, research materials, scripts, vinyl recordings, songbooks and related materials for six motion pictures.
System Requirements
Motion picture sound tracks -- Sound discs -- 33 1/3 rpm.
Biography of Richard M. and Robert B. Sherman
Brothers Richard M. and Robert B. Sherman composed music and lyrics for more motion-picture musicals than any other songwriting team in film history, including several Walt Disney productions. The Sherman brothers were the sons of Russian-Jewish immigrants. Their father was also a famous songwriter, Al Sherman, who wrote Tin Pan Alley. Robert B. Sherman was born in December of 1925, and his brother Richard M. was born June of 1928. Together the duo received various accolades including two Academy Awards and five Golden Globe Awards. In 1976, they received a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame and in 2008, the National Medal of the Arts. The brothers' music is featured in films, stage productions, TV shows, and theme park songs, and garnered them numerous award nominations and victories. Robert B. Sherman died in 2012.
The pair of brothers founded the music publishing company Music World Corporation in 1958, which would go on to enjoy a landmark relationship with Disney's publishing firm beginning in the 1960s. They wrote many well-known songs for Walt Disney, including their most well-known song, It's a Small World (After All) written in 1964. The brothers worked directly for Walt Disney until his death in 1966, after which they left the company. In 1968, their first non-Disney work was produced- Chitty Chitty Bang Bang. The production earned the pair their third Academy Award nomination. In the 2000s the pair wrote six more songs for Chitty, the stage adaptation of their hit film. In the 1970s the brothers returned to Disney and worked on films like The Jungle Book and The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh, as well as many non-Disney affiliated films.
Scope and Content
This collection contains music scores, notes, research materials, scripts, vinyl recordings, songbooks and related materials for six motion pictures, including The Jungle Book, Winnie the Pooh, and Chitty Chitty Bang Bang.
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
There are no known other archival collections created by Richard M. and Robert B. Sherman at the date of processing.
The collection material was donated by Richard M. and Robert B. Sherman.
Access Terms
Walt Disney Productions.; Motion picture music -- Scores.; Animated films -- United States.; Children's films -- United States.; Scores.; Song books.; Scripts.; Film stills.; Phonograph records.; Composers.; Lyricists.; Winnie the Pooh and the honey tree (Motion picture); Chitty chitty bang bang (Motion picture); Happiest millionaire (Motion picture); Jungle book (Motion picture); One and only, genuine, original family band (Motion picture)
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Music; Performing Arts
  - Chitty Chitty Bang Bang:
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Magazine Articles/ Posters, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - Music Scores, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Notes, undated (Box 1)
    - Screenplay by Roald Dahl, November 22, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Song Lyrics, undated (Box 1)
    - Original Cast Soundtrack vinyl record, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Music Sheets, undated (Box 2)
  - The Happiest Millionaire:
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Lyrics, undated (Box 1)
    - Music Scores, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - Notes, undated (Box 1)
    - Program, 1967 (Box 1-2)
    - Reviews, undated (Box 1)
    - Screenplay, 1963, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Shooting Script, April 1966 (Box 1)
    - Original Cast Soundtrack vinyl record, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Music Sheets, undated (Box 2)
  - The Jungle Book:
    - Lyrics, undated (Box 1)
    - Music Scores (digital copies available), 1967 (Box 1)
    - Notes, undated (Box 1)
    - Screenplay, undated (Box 1)
    - Original Cast Soundtrack vinyl record, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Music Sheets, undated (Box 2)
  - My Philidelphia Father:
    - Lyrics, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Screenplay, December 7, 1963 (Box 1)
  - The One and Only Genuine, Original Family Band:
    - Conversion from Straight Drama to Musical by Hawley, Lowell S., October 11, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Lyrics, undated (Box 1)
    - Music Scores, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - Musical Script, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Screenplay, September 15, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Story Outline, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Original Cast Soundtrack vinyl record, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Music Sheets, undated (Box 2)
  - Winnie the Pooh Series:
    - Lyrics, undated (Box 1)
    - Music Scores, 1963, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Notes, undated (Box 1)
    - Production Outline, August 5, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Reviews, October 27, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Winnie the Pooh and the Honey Tree Screenplay, February 1, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Winnie the Pooh and the Honey Tree vinyl record, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Winnie the Pooh and the Blustery Day vinyl record, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Music Sheets, undated (Box 2)